Kevin W. Hoffman

Product Manager • Designer • Developer

• Website: kevinwhoffman.com

• Email: kevin@kevinwhoffman.com

Twitter: @kevinwhoffman
Location: Pittsburgh, PA

Nation

After 10 years of user interface design and development, I found myself gradually assuming more responsibility for the management and long-term vision of the products I was working on. I eventually embraced the role of product manager completely and am now looking to apply that experience as part of a team that is pushing the web forward.

Experience

Impress.org, LLC

After getting started as a Web Developer at Impress.org, I was promoted to Senior Web Developer and then Product Manager of the flagship product <u>GiveWP</u>—a WordPress donation plugin with over 100,000 active installations.

▼ Product Manager (Mar 2019–Nov 2020)

- Led product development of the GiveWP core plugin and its ecosystem of 30+ add-ons for WordPress.
- Planned and managed six-week development cycles with a fixed time and variable scope.
- Provided text and video updates to Marketing, Support, and Customer Success teams throughout development.
- Established a feedback system to aggregate feature requests, bug reports, and integrations submitted by employees and users.
- · Automated builds and deployments via GitHub actions.

▼ Senior Web Developer (Oct 2017–Mar 2019)

- Led design and development of <u>WP Business Reviews</u>—a WordPress reviews plugin—which involved API integration with social media platforms.
- Produced promotional video, website, and graphics for WP Business Reviews.
- · Wrote documentation for internal processes and customer-facing products.

▼ Web Developer (Oct 2016–Oct 2017)

- Programmed WordPress plugins that added new features and integrations to GiveWP.
- Triaged feature requests and bug reports submitted by customers and the open source community.

Kevin W. Hoffman Design, LLC

▼ Owner (May 2013-Present)

- Design, develop, and manage complete websites for clients in need of a web presence with a content management system.
- Provide photography, videography, and graphic design to supplement websites.

Acosta Marketing Group

▼ Senior Web Designer (Jun 2012–May 2013)

- Designed responsive microsites for brands such as Starbucks, Seattle's Best Coffee, and Heinz Ketchup to promote seasonal offerings.
- Worked within the constraints of style guides to create content that fit in seamlessly alongside the parent brand.

Skills

- User interface design and prototyping (Figma, Sketch, Photoshop)
- · Deep familiarity with Figma (auto layout, variants, interactive components) and FigJam
- Understanding of the relationship between design and code and the tools necessary to bring the two together
- Management of shared component libraries and design systems (Figma, Sketch)
- Creation of media-rich presentations to pitch new products and features
- DevOps contributions that streamline product development and deployment (GitHub actions, shell scripts, Slack automations)
- Programming (HTML, CSS, Sass, JS, TypeScript, React, PHP, C#)
- Open-source software development (contributions to the WordPress project)
- Version Control (Git, GitHub)
- Video production and motion graphics (Final Cut Pro X, After Effects)

Education

Drexel University

▼ Bachelor of Science, Digital Media (Sep 2005–Jun 2009)

- · Drexel University SIGGRAPH Chapter
- · Pennoni Honors College

References are available upon request. I look forward to discussing this opportunity with you soon, and invite you to visit my personal site at <u>kevinwhoffman.com</u>. Thank you!